Finding Aid for Robert C. Stempel papers, 1965-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Energy Conversion Devices, 1993-2007
  - Power-point presentations (compact discs) given by RCS on behalf of Energy Conversion Devices, 2002-2006; 53 optical disks CDs
    - Presentation, January 23, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Ovonics Press Conference, Akron, OH, April 27, 2006 (Box 35)
    - NASDAQ 17 Investor Program, London, June 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation to Piper Jaffray, July 10, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation to Dow Automotive, July 11, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation to UBS Investment Research, July 13, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Presentation, July 21, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation to Natews Bleichroeder, July 26, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation, Akron Hydrogen, August 2, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Presentation to Citigroup Investment Research, August 17, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Ovonic Hydrogen Systems, Akron Investor Meetings, September 2006 (Box 35)
    - Fall Road Rally Event, Bloomingdale, IL, Driving Towards the Emerging Hydrogen Economy, October 6, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Ovonic Hydrogen Systems, Presentation to Board of Directors, November 3, 2006 (Box 35)
    - Greenville, Top Secret, April 23, 2007 (Box 35)
    - GM Solar Power Comeback (Box 35)
    - Akron (Box 35)
    - Bexco (Box 35)
    - 19th International Electric Vehicle Symposium & Exhibition (Box 35)
    - DP -- Diesel (Box 35)
  - Videocassettes (VHS)
    - Unlabeled, undated; 2 tapes (Box 36)
    - Bloomfield Community Television, Michigan on Wall Street, Warren Pierce Host; Energy Conversion Devices, Stan Ovshinsky/Robert Stempel, undated (Box 36)
    - Eisbrenner Public Relations, ECD/EV Global Motors, Press Conference, undated; 2 tapes (Box 36)
    - Electric Vehicle Association of the Americas, undated (Box 36)
    - Hydrogen, The Matter of Safety, undated (Box 36)
    - 1997 ECD Annual Meeting, Time Code Window Burn, January 16, 1997, 2 tapes (Box 36)
    - 1996 ECD Annual Meeting, Revised 2, January 28, 1997 (Box 36)
    - Highlights of GMATV Press, Conference and North American Auto Show, January 4, 1998 (Box 36)
    - GMC, ATV Videowall Off-Screen Master, January 8, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Eisbrenner Public Relations, ECD/EV Global Motors, Press Coverage, February 1998 (Box 36)
    - Excerpt from the White House Conference on Global Change, February 2, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Highlights from EV Global Motors & Energy Conversion Devices, Press Conference and Tour, February 10, 1998 (Box 36)
    - EV Global Motors & Energy Conversion Devices Press Conference and Tour, February 10, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Highlights of GM Advanced Technology Vehicles Press Conference (Short Version), February 11, 1998 (Box 36)
    - United Solar Systems "The Power to Change the World", February 11, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Highlights of Energy Conversion Devices, Inc. 1997 Annual Meeting, February 19, 1998 (Box 36)
    - ECD Analysts Video, Final, April 20, 1998 (Box 36)
    - President Bill Clinton, HUD/Path-LA, CA (Short Version), May 4, 1998 (Box 36)
    - President Clinton & Bob Vila Speaking at Inauguration of PATH (Partnership for Advancing Technology in Housing), May 4, 1998 (Box 36)
    - Ovonic Battery, Compilation Reel, June 30, 1998 (Box 36)
    - ECD, Ovonic Battery Compilation Reel, September 4, 1998 (Box 37)
    - Jason X-Expedition Prologue, 1999 (Box 37)
    - Jason Foundation for Education, Jason IX Highlights, 1999 (Box 37)
    - Highlights, ECD, Inc. 1998 Annual Meeting, April 7, 1999 (Box 37)
    - Chrysler, A Quest for Excellence, August 31, 1999 (Box 37)
    - BCBSM Orientation Video, "What Does It Mean to be Blue?", October 26, 1999 (Box 37)
    - 2000 Honors Assembly, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Presentation, Full Contact Disc Brake, Electromagnetic Newtech Brake, Newtech Mecatronic Sensor, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Highlights, Texaco, Inc. & ECD, Inc, Press Conference, May 2, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Highlights, Texaco, Inc. & ECD, Inc, Press Conference, tc/wb dub, May 2, 2000 (Box 37)
    - 2000 Tour de Sol, Washington DC, Comments by Robert Stempel, May 18, 2000 (Box 37)
    - ECD, Transforming the Future, June 5, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Honors and Awards Ceremony, 2001 (Box 37)
    - Energy Conversion Devices, Action News at 5, WXYZ-TV (ABC) Detroit, April 3, 2001 (Box 37)
    - ECD, Transforming the Future, May 30, 2001 (Box 37)
    - Highlights, Texaco Ovonic Battery Systems LLC, Press Conference, July 18, 2001 (Box 37)
    - Highlights, Freedom Car Press Announcement, January 9, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Energy Conversion Devices, Local First News at 6, WDIV-TV, January 24, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Robert Stempel on Alternative Automobiles, Money Gang, CNNfn Cable Network National, March 1, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Earth First, Solar Plant in Auburn Hills, June 19, 2002 (Box 37)
    - Ovonic Solar Solutions, Unmixed, Roughcut, June 21, 2002 (Box 37)
    - CNN, February 2003 (Box 37)
- Speeches / Conferences / Presentations
  The Speeches / Conferences / Presentations series mainly covers the period when Stempel was with General Motors.
  - 1965-1966, 1973-1978 (Box 38)
  - 1978-1981 (Box 39)
  - 1987-1994 (Box 40)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - 1996 (Box 42)
- Organizational Affiliations, Responsibilities, and Interests
  The Organizational Affiliations, Responsibilities, and Interests series documents Stempel's leadership within the National Commission Against Drunk Driving and his participation as a member of Presidential Business Delegation to Asia and the Pacific, December 30, 1991-January 10, 1992.
  - Oakland County Business Roundtable (Box 43)
  - National Commission Against Drunk Driving (Box 43)
  - Council of Great Lakes Industries (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 44)
  - Presidential Business Delegation to Asia and the Pacific, December 30, 1991-January 10, 1992 (Box 45)
    (also includes records of U.S.--Japan Business Council and meetings of Japan-U.S. Business Conference)
  - Presidential Business Delegation to Asia and the Pacific, December 30, 1991-January 10, 1992 (Box 46)
  - Great Lakes Alliance (Box 47)
    (representing domestic automakers and their suppliers; the alliance was formed to capitalize on President Clinton's Technology Initiative and the 1992 National Energy Policy Act; Stempel was chairman)
  - GM Sunraycer; Sunrayce (Box 48)
- Background / Personal information
  The Background / Personal information series is highlighted by the transcript of an oral history interview RCS gave relating to his career with General Motors. There are also hundreds of letters he received following various GM promotions and when he resigned as chairman and chief executive officer.
  - Vita and other biographical information (Box 49)
  - Awards various (Box 49)
    (include photographs of award plaques and other ceremonial memorabilia)
  - Transcript of oral history interview with RCS relating to his career with General Motors, 1998 (Box 49)
  - Worcester Polytechnic Institute (Box 49)
    (include photo upon occasion of receiving honorary degree)
  - Clippings
    - (some gaps), 1966-1994; 11 folders (Box 49)
    - Stan Ovshinsky, articles about (Box 49)
  - Kidnapping of his son Timothy, 1975
    - Binder of material relating to the crime and to the subsequent prosecution; include court testimony, statements of Timothy, etc. (Box 49)
    - Clippings (Box 49)
      (sample)
    - Letters of support upon the return of his son, November 1975 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence (miscellaneous), 1954-2007 (Box 49)
  - RCS business cards (Box 49)
  - Letters of congratulations (Box 50)
    - RCS appointment as Special Assistant to the GM President, 1973 (Box 50)
    - RCS appointment as Chevrolet Director of Engineering, 1975 (Box 50)
    - RCS elected GM President and Chief Operating Officer, 1987
      - Family and friends (Box 50)
      - Business associates / Outside firms (Box 50)
      - GM dealers / GM associates (Box 50)
    - RCS elected GM Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, August 1990
      - GM business associates (Box 50)
      - Business associates -- Outside firms, 2 folders (Box 50)
      - Friends and acquaintances (Box 50)
      - Government officials (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous, include writers and other media, union officials, etc. (Box 50)
    - Following the announcement of his resignation, October-December 1992; 4 folders (Box 51)
    - Get well cards following his elective surgery, 1992; 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Address book and card file; also trays of business cards (Box 52)
    (mainly from the period after RCS left GM)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials includes materials from throughout RCS's career. It includes photographs and slides from through his life. There are other visual materials (films and videotapes) in other series as indicated in this finding aid.
  - Photographs
    - Portraits (Box 53)
    - Stempel with Presidents Ronald Reagan and George H.W. Bush; also Mayor Edward Koch and other public figures (Box 53)
    - Stempel with General Motors executives, company colleagues and friends (Box 53)
      (include Pete Estes, Roger Smith)
      (see also oversize folder UAm)
    - 1970s (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 53)
    - Adam Opel AG, 1981-1982
      - (photos of meetings, plant tours, etc.), 1981-1982; 3 folders (Box 53)
      - General Motors Austria Werke Ges.m.b.H. (Box 53)
    - (Indianapolis 500, etc.), 1982 (Box 53)
    - (Corvette, Bowling Green KY plant, 1982 (Box 53)
    - (Great Lakes Region Service Supremacy Seminar, May 12, 1983) (Box 53)
    - Visit to GM facilities in Brazil, May 1988 (Box 53)
    - Export Vision Conference, circa 1990 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 53)
    - Ca. RCS and Owen Bieber shaking hands around the bargaining table, 1990 (Folder 1)
      (located in UAm)
    - 1991 visit to the White House, meeting with Vice President Quayle, June 12, 1991 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 53)
    - (Milford Proving Ground), 1992 (Box 53)
    - 1992 (visit to GM Asian Technical Center, January 10, 1992 (Box 53)
    - (visit to Italy with Stan Ovshinsky), 1995 (Box 53)
    - President's Water Meeting, February 6, 2003 (Box 53)
    - With Stan Ovshinsky and others, 2000s (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous, 2002-2003 (Box 53)
    - Energy Conversion Devices (with Stan Ovshinsky) (Box 53)
    - Album (Adam Opel vehicles: Corsea, Kadett, Techno, etc.), 1981 (Box 54)
    - Album: Photographs and letters, receiving awards, letters from dignitaries, 1987-1992 (Box 54)
    - Album: Sunraycer, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Album: Roger Smith and Owen Bieber and others visiting the Saturn Plant in Spring Hill, TN, September 1990 (Box 54)
    - Album: Saturn, designers and at auto show (Box 54)
    - Album: Texaco Ovonic Battery System, Springboro, Ohio plant groundbreaking, October 29, 2002 (Box 54)
    - Album Robert Stempel visits China, 2003 (Box 54)
    - Album: Cobasys Grand Opening, Orion, MI, May 18, 2005 (Box 54)
  - Slides
    - Various presentations: slide carousels and slide boxes:
      - Presentation on fuel economy and catalytic conversion, 1974 (Box 55)
      - 1993 Chicago Manufacturing Institute, April 7, 1993 (Box 55)
      - RCS talk on energy and drivetrain trends, 2001 (Box 55)
      - Miscellaneous unidentified (Box 55)
      - "What the Automotive World Is Coming To?" Presentation to Automotive News World Congress, circa 1980 (Box 56)
      - Lecture "Automotive Competition and the Productivity Challenge", October 7, 1982 (Box 56)
      - ECD Company Overview (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous unidentified (Box 56)
- Audio Cassettes
  The Audio Cassettes are recordings of Stempel's appearances on various radio programs as well as other public presentations.
  - E.N. Cole on WJR Sunday, July 19, 1970 (Box 56)
  - Q & A following Stempel and Lund Remarks at Long-Lead Preview, July 13, 1976 (Box 56)
  - Stempel, GM, Pontiac Motor Division, Gen. Motors Co., January 1, 1979 (Box 56)
  - Stempel on WJR, November 12, 1997 (Box 56)
  - Warren Pierce Radio Show, 1310 AM, November 18, 1997 (Box 56)
  - Energy Conversion Devices, November 15, 2000 (Box 56)
  - Jeb Bass, WSVL AM & FM Shelbyville, Ind., undated (Box 56)
  - Pontiac Revs up for the 80's, undated (Box 56)
  - Ovonic Nickel Metal Hydride, GM, undated (Box 56)